[
    {
        "question": "Full form of PHP is?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) PHP stands for Hypertext preprocessor",
        "options": [
            "Pretext Hypertext Processor",
            "Hypertext preprocessor",
            "Preprocessor Home page",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the default file extension of PHP among the following.",
        "answer": "Answer: C) The default file extension of PHP is .php",
        "options": [
            ".xml",
            ".html",
            ".php",
            ".ph"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What type of language is PHP?",
        "answer": "Answer: A) PHP is a server-side scripting language.",
        "options": [
            "Server-side scripting",
            "Client-side scripting",
            "User-side scripting",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the correct syntax of PHP.",
        "answer": "Answer: D) The correct syntax is <?php?>",
        "options": [
            "<php>",
            "<?php>",
            "?php?",
            "<?php?>"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the equivalent of the statement : $sub -= $sub.",
        "answer": "Answer: B) $sub -= $sub is equivalent to $sub = $sub - $sub",
        "options": [
            "$sub = $sub - 1",
            "$sub = $sub - $sub",
            "$sub = $sub - $sub - 1",
            "$sub = $sub"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Total ways in which user a print output in PHP is -",
        "answer": "Answer: A) Output can be printed in 2 ways i.e. echo and print.",
        "options": [
            "2",
            "3",
            "4",
            "5"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Among echo and print, which is faster?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) echo is comparatively faster than print.",
        "options": [
            "print",
            "echo",
            "Both have the same speed",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In PHP, variable names must start with which of the following.",
        "answer": "Answer: D) Variable names must follow all of the above.",
        "options": [
            "No numbers",
            "Letters",
            "Underscore",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Is PHP variable case sensitive?",
        "answer": "Answer: A) PHP variables are case-sensitive.",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False",
            "Depends on variable",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Total variable scope in PHP is?",
        "answer": "",
        "options": [
            "",
            "",
            "",
            ""
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the incorrect data type among the following.",
        "answer": "Answer: B) void is not a data type in PHP.",
        "options": [
            "Objects",
            "void",
            "Null",
            "Resources"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Total looping techniques supported by PHP are?",
        "answer": "Answer: D) PHP supports 4 types of looping techniques - for, while, do-while,for-each loop.",
        "options": [
            "1",
            "22",
            "3",
            "4"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose whether true or false: the do-while loop is an exit control loop.",
        "answer": "Answer: B) True. the do-while loop is an exit control loop.",
        "options": [
            "False",
            "True",
            "Depends on the condition",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose whether true or false: while loop is an exit control loop.",
        "answer": "Answer: A) False. while loop is an entry control loop.",
        "options": [
            "False",
            "True",
            "Depends on the condition",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the function among the following, which is not built-in.",
        "answer": "Answer: B) fclosed() isn’t a built-in function in PHP.",
        "options": [
            "fopen()",
            "fclosed()",
            "gettype()",
            "print_r()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Functions in PHP should start with which of the following keyword?",
        "answer": "Answer: c) Functions in PHP should start with the keyword function.",
        "options": [
            "def",
            "fun",
            "function",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Total types of the array in PHP is?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) There are a total of 3 types of arrays in PHP.",
        "options": [
            "2",
            "3",
            "4",
            "5"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Index of an array by default starts with which of the following in PHP?",
        "answer": "Answer: A) Index of arrays starts with 0 in PHP.",
        "options": [
            "0",
            "-1",
            "1",
            "2"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "trim() in PHP is used for?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) trim() removes whitespaces.",
        "options": [
            "Removes uppercase alphabet",
            "Removes whitespaces",
            "Removes lowercase alphabet",
            "Removes underscore"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Another term used for Objects is?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) Objects are also known as instances.",
        "options": [
            "template",
            "reference",
            "instances",
            "class"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Using which keyword is the object created?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) new keyword is used for creating the object.",
        "options": [
            "object",
            "new",
            "create",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Another name of the constructor is?",
        "answer": "Answer: D) Constructors are also known as magic functions.",
        "options": [
            "Key function",
            "Automatic function",
            "Find function",
            "Magic function"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the following options, choose the term which is used to refer to methods within the class itself.",
        "answer": "Answer: A) this keyword is used to refer to methods within the class itself.",
        "options": [
            "this",
            "public",
            "private",
            "protected"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In which version of PHP was Type Hinting introduced?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) Type Hinting was introduced in PHP 5.",
        "options": [
            "PHP 6",
            "PHP 4",
            "PHP 5",
            "PHP 5.3"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Among the following functions, choose the one which accepts any number of parameters.",
        "answer": "Answer: D) func_get_args() can accepts any number of parameters.",
        "options": [
            "get_argv()",
            "func_get_argv()",
            "get_argc()",
            "func_get_args()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used to find files?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) glob() is used to find files.",
        "options": [
            "file()",
            "glob()",
            "get_file()",
            "fold()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the function which is used to compress a string.",
        "answer": "Answer: A) gzcompress() is used to compress a string.",
        "options": [
            "gzcompress()",
            "compress()",
            "zip()",
            "zip_compress()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following function is used to sort array in descending order?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) rsort() is used to sort array in descending order.",
        "options": [
            "dsort()",
            "asort()",
            "rsort()",
            "sort()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the correct way to invoke a method among the following.",
        "answer": "Answer: D) To invoke a method $object->methodName(); is used.",
        "options": [
            "object::methodName();",
            "object -> methodName();",
            "$object::methodName();",
            "$object->methodName();"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the option which prevents a method from being overridden by a subclass?",
        "answer": "Answer: A) Final is the method scope which prevents a method from being overridden by a subclass.",
        "options": [
            "Final",
            "Protected",
            "Static",
            "Abstract"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In PHP, how are constructors recognized?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) In PHP, constructors recognized by function__construct().",
        "options": [
            "function_construct()",
            "classname()",
            "function__construct()",
            "_construct()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the feature, which allows calling one or more methods or functions in single instruction?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) Method chaining allows to call one or more methods or functions in a single instruction.",
        "options": [
            "Method adding",
            "Method chaining",
            "Method including",
            "Typecasting"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Total error levels available in PHP are?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) PHP has a total of 16 error levels.",
        "options": [
            "17",
            "16",
            "15",
            "14"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Error level E_ERROR denotes?",
        "answer": "Answer: D) E_ERROR denotes a Fatal run-time error.",
        "options": [
            "Near-fatal error",
            "Compile-time error",
            "Fatal compile-time error",
            "Fatal run-time error"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the options among the following which invokes the exception class.",
        "answer": "Answer: C) throw new exception() invokes the exception class.",
        "options": [
            "new exception()",
            "throws new expection()",
            "throw new expection()",
            "New throws exception()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the options among the following which generates unique ids",
        "answer": "Answer: B) uniqueid() is function which generates unique ids.",
        "options": [
            "md5()",
            "uniqueid()",
            "id()",
            "mdid()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Find the output of the code below:<?PHP\n ECHO CHR(52);\n?>",
        "answer": "Answer: D) ASCII value of 4 is 52, hence the output is 4.",
        "options": [
            "1",
            "2",
            "3",
            "4"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Find the output of the code below:<?PHP\n ECHO ORD(“HI”);\n?>",
        "answer": "Answer: A) The ASCII value of H is 104 and ORD returns the ASCII value of the first character.",
        "options": [
            "104",
            "103",
            "106",
            "209"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the function which adds a value at the end of an array?",
        "answer": "Answer: D) array_push() adds a value at the end of an array.",
        "options": [
            "into_array()",
            "inend_array()",
            "array_unshift()",
            "array_push()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Find the output of the code below:<?PHP\n$arr = ARRAY(12,5,2);\n ECHO (ARRAY_PRODUCT($A));\n?>",
        "answer": "Answer: C) ARRAY_PRODUCT returns the product of all the elements of the array.",
        "options": [
            "60",
            "10",
            "120",
            "24"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following function is used to sort arrays in the natural order?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) natcasesort() is used to sort arrays in the natural order.",
        "options": [
            "dsort()",
            "natcasesort()",
            "naturalsort()",
            "casesort()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the property scope not supported by PHP.",
        "answer": "Answer: D) The property scope final is not supported by PHP.",
        "options": [
            "public",
            "static",
            "friendly",
            "final"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "From which of the following class does the child class inherits?\nChild class\nSuper class\nBase class\nParent class",
        "answer": "Answer: C). The child class inherits from a parent class and base class.",
        "options": [
            "Only 2",
            "Only 2 and 3",
            "Only 3 and 4",
            "Only 1 and 4"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "To implement overloading, which of the following magic method used?",
        "answer": "Answer: A) __call is used to implement overloading in PHP.",
        "options": [
            "__call",
            "__invoke",
            "__unset",
            "__wakeup"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Full form of SPL is?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) SPL stands for Standard PHP library.",
        "options": [
            "Source PHP library",
            "Source PHP list",
            "Standard PHP library",
            "Standard PHP list"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Total types of filtering present in PHP?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) PHP has a total of 2 filtering types.",
        "options": [
            "1",
            "2",
            "3",
            "4"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the regular expression which matches any expression string having zero or one P?",
        "answer": "Answer: C) P? Is the regular expression that matches any expression string having zero or one P.",
        "options": [
            "P+",
            "P*",
            "P?",
            "P#"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Full form of POSIX is?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) POSIX stands for Portable Operating system interface for Unix.",
        "options": [
            "Portable Operating system interface for Linux",
            "Portable Operating system interface for Unix",
            "Portative Operating system interface for Linux",
            "Portative Operating system interface for Unix"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the function which converts a string to uppercase.",
        "answer": "Answer: C) strtoupper() converts a string to uppercase.",
        "options": [
            "uppercase()",
            "str_uppercase()",
            "strtoupper()",
            "struppercase()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The function FILESIZE() returns the size of the file in?",
        "answer": "Answer: B) FILESIZE() returns the size of the file in bytes.",
        "options": [
            "KB",
            "Bytes",
            "GB",
            "bits"
        ]
    }
]